Guide to the Warren Ives Bradley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Warren Ives Bradley papers
1863-1880
MS 924
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Chiefly fragments of manuscripts from Warren Ives Bradley's published books. Also included is a scrapbook of reviews, household expense lists and photographs of Bradley and his brother, Oliver Burritt Bradley.
Gaylord, Glance, 1847-1868
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of A. N. Manross, 1961.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Warren Ives Bradley (1847-1868) wrote books for children under the pen-name Glance Gaylord. This collection consists primarily of manuscripts, some of which appear to be portions of his fifteen published books. There are also notes and content lists for the books, a scrapbook of reviews of several of Bradley's books, two letters from Henry Hoyt to Bradley about publishing, and an agreement between Bradley and the publishers A. Graves and Henry A. Young. Unrelated to Bradley's writing career are a series of household expense lists, and photographs of Bradley and his brother, Oliver Burritt Bradley. There is, finally, a copy of Bradley's obituary, "A Memoir of Warren Ives Bradley."
Biographical / Historical
Warren Ives Bradley was born in Bristol, Connecticut, on March 27, 1847. He was the author of numerous children's books, written under the pen name Glance Gaylord. Among his writings were Boys at Dr. Murray's (1866), Uncle Donnie's Home (1866), Gay Cottage (1867), After Years (1868), Mr. Pendleton's Cup (1869). He died in Bristol, on June 15, 1868.
Children's literature; Cost and standard of living; Literature -- History and criticism; Authors; Gaylord, Glance, 1847-1868
- Inventory
  - "A Memoir of Warren Ives Bradley", undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Writings, 1863-1867, undated (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Writings: fragments, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Content lists, notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook of book reviews, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Publishers' agreement, 1866 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Household expense lists, 1866-1867, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)